<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Superhero Genes - Base</name>
  <author>alite</author>
  <packageId>SuperheroGenesBase.Mod</packageId>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.4</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>ludeon.rimworld.biotech</packageId>
      <displayName>Biotech</displayName>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>

  <loadAfter>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
    <li>ceteam.combatextended</li>
    <li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</li>
    <li>sarg.alphagenes</li>
    <li>Sov.Homelander</li>
  </loadAfter>

  <description>
Ever wanted your pawns to be able to lift extreme weights? Want them to be able to research things at frankly ridiculous speeds? This mod allows you to give pawns some of the more mundane super powers, like super strength and super speed. Much like in superhero movies, there is little balance in what they can do, but you didn't come here for common sense. In this base, there are 3 categories of powers, and 6 powers within each one, each power influencing a different aspect of the pawn, along with a straggler or two as a bonus. All superhero genes, from this mod or any that may or may not be made after this, have a prerequisite superhero gene that provides boosts to numerous aspects of the pawn at no cost.

The three categories are Super, Unsuper, and AntiSuper. The supers increase stats even further beyond the what the base gene provides, while unsuper genes negate the base bonus for that type. Antisuper genes provide another penalty in addition to the unsuper version, and in exchange they increase metabolic efficiency by a decent chunk.

This mod won't add the ability to turn invisible, shoot fire, or fly, mostly because [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2891845502]Alpha Genes[/url] already does an amazing job of adding those kinds of abilities. If enough people request it, I may create a mod that integrates some genes from other mods into the supergenes section, probably with lowered costs to match the unbalanced nature of the rest of the superhero genes, but I don't forsee people being very interested in this mod, let alone expansions. 

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2980131746]Superhero Genes - Villains and Stereotypes[/url] adds xenotypes that use these genes and a contantly hostile faction. It's separate from this one so that people don't have a bunch of extra xenotypes filling their list, or a hostile faction of strong opponents disrupting their colony constantly. I'm also thinking of making an additional mod that restricts superhero genes more by restricting the types of normal genes that can be taken with the superhero gene more, but that is going to be delayed based on whatever my work schedule says and how interested I am in it at any given moment.

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2986697224]Superhero Genes - Supers Everywhere[/url] gives all xenotypes the superhero gene, and replaces many negative genes with anti-super genes. The end result is that all of the negative aspects of each xenotype become more significant, and if you're using Villains and Stereotypes it makes it easier to find pawns that can fight Villains one on one.


[url=https://steamcommunity.com/id/alite/myworkshopfiles/?appid=294100]Easy link to all of my Rimworld mods[/url]
[url=https://github.com/KonradHeinser/SuperheroGenesBase][img]https://i.imgur.com/kTkpTOE.png[/img][/url]
[url=https://ko-fi.com/alite56114][img]https://i.imgur.com/Utx6OIH.png[/img][/url]

For those who are wondering, yes, I have added a CE compatibility patch.

The primary types added by this mod are durability, healing, intelligence, perception, persuasion, precision, speed, and strength. These types contain genes that affect various stats and capacities conceptually related to the category. For example, durability alters a pawn's defenses while intelligence improves the rate that the pawn gets research and hacking points. Because many of these genes affect a wide range of things, I'm not going to write all of their effects here. The Superhero Genes category should be near the top of the list in the xenotype editor, so ideally it won't be too hard for everyone to find them.

While genes from this mod are not balanced for the game, they are supposed to be balanced for each other. If any one superhero gene feels useless or overpowered compared to other genes in its category, let me know. A monster might have eaten my balance when I wasn't looking.
  </description>
</ModMetaData>

