<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<LanguageData>
	<SHG_Hemomancer_Starfish>{0}'s clump of hemogen has successfully developed.</SHG_Hemomancer_Starfish>
    <SHG_GeneticRomanceChance>Carrier Gene(s)</SHG_GeneticRomanceChance>
    <AbilityHomeTeleport>Skip to random area in home</AbilityHomeTeleport>
    <AbilityMapTeleport>Skip to random area in map</AbilityMapTeleport>
    <AbilityTileTeleport>Skip to tile</AbilityTileTeleport>
    <AbilityPassableOnly>Only passable tiles can be picked</AbilityPassableOnly>
    <AbilityTooFarToTeleport>This tile is too far for this teleportation ability</AbilityTooFarToTeleport>
    <SHG_NeedOffsets>Base need offsets:</SHG_NeedOffsets>
    <SHG_Random>Random option</SHG_Random>
    <SHG_DestinationBlocked>Something is blocking the destination.</SHG_DestinationBlocked>
    <SHG_Biome>{0} is not a viable biome to start from.</SHG_Biome>
    <MessagePawnArrived>A pawn has arrived at their destination and needs new orders.</MessagePawnArrived>

    <!--Item Creator-->
    <AbilityWater>Must target an area without water.</AbilityWater>
    <AbilityNoWater>Must target an area filled with water.</AbilityNoWater>
    <AbilityPollution>Must target an area without pollution.</AbilityPollution>
    <AbilityNoPollution>Must target an area filled with pollution.</AbilityNoPollution>
    <AbilityNoRoof>Must target an area that is completely roofed.</AbilityNoRoof>
    <AbilityPlant>Must target an area that has no plants.</AbilityPlant>
    <AbilityThing>Must target an area that has nothing in it.</AbilityThing>
    <AbilityGameCondition>An existing map condition is obstructing the ability from working.</AbilityGameCondition>

    <!--Ability Validator Stuff-->
    <AbilityNoTargetGeneOne>Target must have the {0} gene for this ability to work.</AbilityNoTargetGeneOne>
    <AbilityNoTargetGene>Target is missing a required gene for this ability to work.</AbilityNoTargetGene>
    <AbilityTargetGeneOne>Target has the {0} gene, preventing this ability from working.</AbilityTargetGeneOne>
    <AbilityTargetGene>Target has a gene  preventing this ability from working.</AbilityTargetGene>

    <AbilityNoTargetHediffOne>Target must have the {0} hediff for this ability to work.</AbilityNoTargetHediffOne>
    <AbilityNoTargetHediff>Target is missing a required hediff for this ability to work.</AbilityNoTargetHediff>
    <AbilityTargetHediffOne>Target has the {0} hediff, preventing this ability from working.</AbilityTargetHediffOne>
    <AbilityTargetHediff>Target has a hediff preventing this ability from working.</AbilityTargetHediff>

    <AbilityNoCasterHediffOne>Caster must have the hediff {0} for this ability to work.</AbilityNoCasterHediffOne>
    <AbilityNoCasterHediff>Caster is missing a required hediff for this ability to work.</AbilityNoCasterHediff>
    <AbilityCasterHediffOne>Caster has the {0} hediff, preventing this ability from working.</AbilityCasterHediffOne>
    <AbilityCasterHediff>Caster has a hediff preventing this ability from working.</AbilityCasterHediff>

    <AbilityGameNoConditionOne>This map is not currently experiencing a(n) {0}, which is required for this ability to work.</AbilityGameNoConditionOne>
    <AbilityGameNoCondition>The map must be experiencing certain conditions for this ability to wrok.</AbilityGameNoCondition>
    <AbilityGameConditionOne>This map is currently experiencing a(n) {0}, which prevents this ability from working.</AbilityGameConditionOne>

    <AbilityWeatherOne>Map currently has bad weather for this ability to work: {0}</AbilityWeatherOne>
    <AbilityNoWeatherOne>Map needs specific weather for this ability to work: {0}</AbilityNoWeatherOne>
    <AbilityNoWeather>Map needs specific weather for this ability to work.</AbilityNoWeather>

    <AbilityTargetLightLevel>Target must be standing in a location with a light level between {0} and {1}</AbilityTargetLightLevel>
    <AbilityCasterLightLevel>Caster must be standing in a location with a light level between {0} and {1}</AbilityCasterLightLevel>
    <AbilityTime>Hour must be between {0} and {1} to use this ability.</AbilityTime>

    <AbilityTargetNoneCheck>Target can't use {0}.</AbilityTargetNoneCheck>
    <AbilityTargetLowCheck>Target's {0} is too low.</AbilityTargetLowCheck>
    <AbilityTargetHighCheck>Target's {0} is too high.</AbilityTargetHighCheck>
    
    <AbilityCasterNoneCheck>Caster can't use {0}.</AbilityCasterNoneCheck>
    <AbilityCasterLowCheck>Caster's {0} is too low.</AbilityCasterLowCheck>
    <AbilityCasterHighCheck>Caster's {0} is too high.</AbilityCasterHighCheck>
        
    <!--DRG Stuff-->
    <ResourceCost>{0} cost</ResourceCost>
    <ResourceGain>{0} gain</ResourceGain>
    <AlertLowResource>Low resource</AlertLowResource>
    <AlertLowResourceDesc>A colonist is runnning out of a resource</AlertLowResourceDesc>
    <NoIngredients>No available packs.</NoIngredients>
    <NotAllowedResource>Resource packs disabled by food restriction.</NotAllowedResource>
    <AutoTakeResourceDesc>This determines whether {PAWN_nameDef} will automatically ingest {RESOURCE} packs when {PAWN_possessive} {RESOURCE} is below {MIN}.\n\nAutomatic ingestion is currently {ONOFF}.</AutoTakeResourceDesc>
    <ConsumeResourceBelow>Consume {0} below</ConsumeResourceBelow>
    <AbilityDisabledNoResourceGene>{0_labelShort} lacks the {1} gene.</AbilityDisabledNoResourceGene>
    <AbilityDisabledNoResource>{0_labelShort} does not have enough {1}.</AbilityDisabledNoResource>
    <AbilityNotBattery>Must target a battery.</AbilityNotBattery>

    <LetterLabelTributeCaravanArrival>{0}</LetterLabelTributeCaravanArrival>
    <LetterTributeCaravanArrival>A {0} from {FACTION_name} is approaching.\n\nThey will accept {1} you offer as tribute. The one who gives over the tribute will receive {FACTION_royalFavorLabel} for {2}.\n\nYou can expect a {0} to arrive {3} as long as you are not enemies with {FACTION_name}.</LetterTributeCaravanArrival>

    <!--Settings stuff-->
    <SHG_ModMenu>Superhero Genes</SHG_ModMenu>

    <SHG_ModName>Superhero Genes - Base (Restart Required for all of these)</SHG_ModName>
    <SHG_ModDescription>Much like the people in superhero stories, pawns with these genes can accomplish incomprehensible feats and slay countless foes with ease. Killing a super often requires extraordinary weapons, or a bigger monster.\n\nThe core module of the Superhero Genes series.\n\nThe checkboxes of each section only hide the options, they do not set anything.</SHG_ModDescription>

    <SHG_CondensedMeteors>    Allow Condensed Meteors</SHG_CondensedMeteors>
    <SHG_CondensedMeteorsDescription>Allows the condensed summons(i.e condensed steel, condensed jade, and condensed components) to appear as rare meteors. If enabled and a meteor lands, it's recommended that you DON'T mine it all immediately for obvious reasons (colony wealth increases).</SHG_CondensedMeteorsDescription>

    <SHG_MultipleMutations>    Multi-Mutation Supers</SHG_MultipleMutations>
    <SHG_MultipleMutationsDescription>Removes the normal limitation of one mutation per superpowered pawn.</SHG_MultipleMutationsDescription>

    <SHG_MultipleArchetypes>    Multi-Archetype Supers</SHG_MultipleArchetypes>
    <SHG_MultipleArchetypesDescription>Removes the normal limitation of one archetype per superpowered pawn. Individual archetypes may have certain things that make them incompatible with other archetypes, but there is no longer a global tag excluding all archetypes.</SHG_MultipleArchetypesDescription>

    <SHG_ExpensiveBase>    Expensive Base</SHG_ExpensiveBase>
    <SHG_ExpensiveBaseDescription>Sets the superhero base gene to have a metabolic efficiency of -8(equal to the bonus gained through taking all of the unsuper genes), and adds a dormant super archetype that is the equivalent of taking all the unsuper genes at once.\n\nWARNING: This will cause all the super creating pills (and stereotypes for those with the Villains mod) to give anti-super genes, which cause massive penalties. It will also cause most of them to give the Super Recluse flaw, which provides strong mood bonuses in small colonies, but causes really high mood penalties in large colonies.</SHG_ExpensiveBaseDescription>

    <SHG_SupersEverywhere>    Supers Everywhere</SHG_SupersEverywhere>
    <SHG_SupersEverywhereDescription>Makes all non-custom xenotypes gain the superhero base gene, and exchange some of their negative genes for their more severe antisuper counterparts. This will also catch xenotypes added by other mods, but because it always errs on the higher metabolic efficiency side, you may end up with some xenotypes with more than +5 metabolic efficiency. I have made some patches to correct some mods, but let me know if there's a particularly aggregious one you'd like taken care of.</SHG_SupersEverywhereDescription>
    <SHG_ArchetypesEverywhere>        Archetypes Everywhere</SHG_ArchetypesEverywhere>
    <SHG_ArchetypesEverywhereDescription>WARNING: If you don't have Multi-Archetype Supers setting active when using this setting then non-vanilla non-super xenotypes may end up losing certain capabilities, which you can check in the xenotype creation menu by looking for inactive archetypes. If you find a xenotype like this you'll have to make a request to me for a compatibility patch.\n\nMakes most non-custom xenotypes that have abilities replace those abilities with a related archetype (some xenotypes will lose a related non-ability gene instead if they lack abilities, granting them abilities and a bonus related to the lost gene).\n\nFor example, pawns with the animal warcall ability will instead have the druid archetype, which gives both the more powerful command animal ability and the tox bolt ability.\n\nThis will make most xenotypes far stronger than they would be with just supers everywhere due to the new abilities and buffs that archetypes provide, and it errs on the side of lower metabolic efficiency to counter the higher ones caused by supers everywhere.\n\nThis setting has limited ability to mess with the xenotypes of other mods. While it will replace their vanilla abilities, other abilities will remain unaffected. This also won't add any major archetypes like hemomancer or psionist, so most hemogen reliant xenotypes won't have much change.</SHG_ArchetypesEverywhereDescription>

    <SHG_ActivatableSuperGenes>    Activatable Super Genes</SHG_ActivatableSuperGenes>
    <SHG_ActivatableSuperGenesDescription>Instead of having all the genes give a bunch of constant bonuses, the bonuses are locked behind an ability that must be activated to receive those boons. If active long enough, the pawn will begin gaining increasing boosts to their consciousness, and ever increasing risk of heart attack. It takes half a day for the side effects to begin appearing.</SHG_ActivatableSuperGenesDescription>
    <SHG_InterruptibleActivatables>        Interruptible Activatables</SHG_InterruptibleActivatables>
    <SHG_InterruptibleActivatablesDescription>Instead of activating almost instantly, the abilities take 10 seconds to activate, making it much harder to use them mid battle.</SHG_InterruptibleActivatablesDescription>

    <SHG_MiddleGrounds>    Middle Ground Basic Super Genes</SHG_MiddleGrounds>
    <SHG_MiddleGroundsDescription>Adds a second option for all of the basic super and antisuper genes. This adds 16 new genes.</SHG_MiddleGroundsDescription>
    <SHG_AllGrounds>        All Ground Basic Super Genes</SHG_AllGrounds>
    <SHG_AllGroundsDescription>Extends the options for all of the basic super and antisuper genes to the maximum extent. This adds 27 new genes in addition to the 16 added by middle ground, for a total of 43 new genes.</SHG_AllGroundsDescription>

    <SHG_RadiomancerOvercharge>    Radiomancer Overcharge</SHG_RadiomancerOvercharge>
    <SHG_RadiomancerOverchargeDescription>While enabled, Energy Armor, Energized Neurons, and Infused Muscles will cause Radiomancers to become overcharged if they reach 120%. While overcharged, the Radiomancer is a danger to most non-super individuals along with many supers for at least 24 hours. This danger applies to both allies and enemies.</SHG_RadiomancerOverchargeDescription>

    <SHG_SuperDrugs_NoTrader>    No Super Drugs in Generic Traders</SHG_SuperDrugs_NoTrader>
    <SHG_SuperDrugs_NoTraderDescription>This option makes it so most traders are incapable of having any super creating drug types in their lists. This won't impact certain super faction traders, nor will it remove any permits that grant them.\n\nWhen combined with the no reward setting, it is usually impossible to get without certain super factions.</SHG_SuperDrugs_NoTraderDescription>
    <SHG_SuperDrugs_NoReward>    No Super Drugs in Generic Rewards</SHG_SuperDrugs_NoReward>
    <SHG_SuperDrugs_NoRewardDescription>This option makes it so none of the super creating drug variants will appear in normal reward sets. This won't impact any reward sets that specifically look for super creating pill types if anything creates a group like that.\n\nWhen combined with the no trader setting, it is usually impossible to get without certain super factions.</SHG_SuperDrugs_NoRewardDescription>

    <SHG_NoPsionicNeurotrainers>    No Psionic Neurotrainers</SHG_NoPsionicNeurotrainers>
    <SHG_NoPsionicNeurotrainersDescription>Normally psionic powers that can be obtained through genes are also findable through neurotrainers to provide another way to obtain them mid-game. If this setting is enabled, they will no longer appear.\n\nThere is a decent chance this will cause an issue if changed mid-save, so use with caution.</SHG_NoPsionicNeurotrainersDescription>

    <!--Cooldown Settings-->
    <SHG_BaseAbilityCooldown>    Longer Ability Cooldowns</SHG_BaseAbilityCooldown>
    <SHG_BaseAbilityCooldownDesc>Increases the base cooldown of most super powers to be whatever is listed here. Most abilities have a cooldown of 1-2 seconds, and this setting will increase a lot of those to a higher value. This won't always impact all abilities since some of them are more akin to toggles, meaning a low cooldown generally doesn't have an actual effect for them. This will never make abilities have a shorter cooldown, and the hemowarrior buffs cap at 12 hour cooldowns, limiting you to 2 tiers of buffs each day.\n\nThis will progressively make supers weaker as their abilities gain longer cooldowns due to them increasingly needing to rely whatever stats their powers provide. This won't increase the power of any of the abilities, nor will it cause any changes to any genes.</SHG_BaseAbilityCooldownDesc>
    <SHG_Disabled>Disabled</SHG_Disabled>
    <SHG_OneHour>One hour</SHG_OneHour>
    <SHG_ThreeHours>Three hours</SHG_ThreeHours>
    <SHG_SixHours>Six hours</SHG_SixHours>
    <SHG_TwelveHours>Twelve hours</SHG_TwelveHours>
    <SHG_OneDay>One day</SHG_OneDay>

    <!--AI Settings-->
    <SHG_SuperAI>Autocast Abilities (Restart Required for any changes)</SHG_SuperAI>
    <SHG_SuperAIDescription>This causes colonists to automatically try to use some of their super abilities when appropriate. This is disabled by default for a few reasons.
\n\nFirst, some may not like the idea of having the pawns they are supposed to be controlling doing things on their own.
\nThe second reason is that this can cause the game to run slower due to the game needing to process more things by itself.
\nAnd the last reason is that, as many of us have probably noticed, AIs have a tendency of getting caught up on the weirdest stuff, acting in ways that don't quite make sense and making it harder for you to play the game.
\n\nMost abilities will not try to activate if the pawn is drafted, but some of them will interrupt you in specific situations(i.e. If autocast healing is enabled, the pawn has a sealing abiltity, and they are bleeding, they will first try to seal their wounds with said ability).
\n\nSecond note, while Hemomancer and Psionist abilities are on the automated lists, they are the last ones used. The order of abilities chosen is Generic Powers > Psionic Powers > Hemomantic Powers > Pool Consuming Powers(if enabled).
\n\nCasting while drafted is a separate option because some people may not like the idea of pawns acting on their own in battle. Usually, the pawn will only autocast while drafted if it does not have a forced job, so you usually don't need to worry about a pawn standing still when you really, really need them to move. One of the most notable exceptions where the pawn will ignore orders is self healing wounds when bleeding a lot, though the only abilities ever available for this purpose have a cast time of one or lower.
</SHG_SuperAIDescription>

    <SHG_AllowPoolUsage>    Allow Life Pool Usage</SHG_AllowPoolUsage>
    <SHG_AllowPoolUsageDescription>Some abilities grant powerful bonuses in the short term, but cause the super to have various debuffs afterwards. If this disabled, then these abilities will never be autocast.\n\nTo avoid having the AI use these abilities when it makes no sense, the only autocast categories that will use this abilty are autocast defense and autocast healing.</SHG_AllowPoolUsageDescription>

    <SHG_AutomaticHealer>    Autocast Healing</SHG_AutomaticHealer>
    <SHG_AutomaticHealerDescription>Makes multiple healing abilities automatically cast, along with the basic revive ability. This will also include the vanilla Coagulate ability as one of the last resort ability-based healing methods.\n\nYou may occassionally be unable to stop a pawn that's reviving a colonist by drafting them due to the nature of the ability. Revival will only be attempted while the pawn is undrafted and there are no enemies on the map. The pawn will also revive forbidden colonist corpses, so you don't need to worry about one being missed that way. If you want to dispose of the corpse rather than revive it, you will need to keep the reviver drafted or manually busy as your other colonists deal with the corpse.</SHG_AutomaticHealerDescription>

    <SHG_AutomaticDefense>    Autocast Defense</SHG_AutomaticDefense>
    <SHG_AutomaticDefenseDescription>Makes multiple defensive abilities automatically cast while the pawn is undrafted. If the pawn is undrafted and finds enemies nearby, then it will use the defensive abilities it has based on the situation. For example, if the pawn is shot at while they have a smokescreen-like ability, said ability may be used to minimize the chances of getting shot more. This will only attempt to use specific abilities from Superhero Genes. The pawn will avoid using abilties if they already have a defensive ability active to ensure they don't just stand there repeatedly buffing themselves when they should be fighting or fleeing.</SHG_AutomaticDefenseDescription>
    <SHG_AutomaticDefenseDrafted>        Drafted Auto-Defense</SHG_AutomaticDefenseDrafted>
    <SHG_AutomaticDefenseDraftedDescription>Pawns will try to use the same abiilties as they would while undrafted in a dangerous situation. This is a separate option because you may encounter situations where pawns will use their defensive abilities in ways that may differ from your play style. The pawn will avoid using abilties if they already have a defensive ability active to ensure they don't just stand there repeatedly buffing themselves when you need them to shoot something.</SHG_AutomaticDefenseDraftedDescription>

    <SHG_AutomaticBuffs>    Autocast Buffs</SHG_AutomaticBuffs>
    <SHG_AutomaticBuffsDescription>While the pawn is undrafted, they will automatically use their hediff adding beneficial abilties as they see fit. If the pawn has stacking abilities (like the hemo-warriors armor buffs), they fall under this category and are only used if A) they don't have a cost, or B) the related resource has reached high enough levels that the AI assumes it's fine. The AI will always seek to keep stacking buffs to just beyond their highest levels (to avoid having it end up lost due to the pawn being drafted for a few hours), but will otherwise ignore them. Drafted pawns also will not use these abilities to avoid situations where they cast abilities at weird times.\n\nFor abilities that normally have a regenerating resource(i.e. Hemomancers due to their high hemogen recovery will automatically use their abilities), the pawn checks their target resource level instead of a static number. If your colony doesn't have a steady resource pack supply and have pawns that need those packs to survive, it is recommended you disable auto-consuming packs for that pawn so they don't constantly consum packs to get themselves to the highest level.</SHG_AutomaticBuffsDescription>

    <SHG_AutomaticDebuff>    Autocast Debuff</SHG_AutomaticDebuff>
    <SHG_AutomaticDebuffDescription>Makes multiple debuffing abilities automatically cast while the pawn is undrafted. If the pawn is undrafted and finds enemies nearby, then it will use the debuffing abilities it has against the pawn they are targetting. This will also cause pawns to try to use berserk abilities on enemies/random animals whenever there are enemies on the map, assuming said abilities don't make the targets attack colonists or non-enemies.\n\nDue to the nature of how pawns think, they don't use when enemies are too close. Also, they only try to use debuffs when set to attack nearby targets, so there will be a middle-ground where enemies are close enough to keep getting debuffed, but not close enough to start attacking.</SHG_AutomaticDebuffDescription>
    <SHG_AutomaticDebuffDrafted>        Drafted Auto-Debuff</SHG_AutomaticDebuffDrafted>
    <SHG_AutomaticDebuffDraftedDescription>Pawns will try to use the same abiilties as they would while undrafted in a dangerous situation. This is a separate option because you may encounter situations where pawns will try to use their debuffing abilities in ways you may not want them to, and keeping it separate gives you an override. The pawn will avoid using abilties if their target already has the debuffing ability active to ensure they don't just stand there repeatedly debuffing the enemy with the same ability.\n\nDue to the nature of how Rimworld handles jobs, pawns will only attempt to use this when interrupted (i.e. ordered to move to a new location, got hit by an enemy, just finished casting an ability, just got drafted, etc). While this is usually not an issue for supers with a large number of abilities, it's recommended to treat this more as an additional help than a primary method of debuffing enemies, as this AI is more reactive than proactive. Drafted Auto-Offense handles some of these issues for pawns that have one or two offensive abilities.</SHG_AutomaticDebuffDraftedDescription>

    <SHG_AutomaticOffense>    Autocast Offense</SHG_AutomaticOffense>
    <SHG_AutomaticOffenseDescription>Makes multiple offensive abilities automatically cast while the pawn is undrafted. If the pawn is undrafted and finds enemies nearby, then it will use the offensive abilities it has based on the situation. For example, if their enemy doesn't have any of the pawn's allies nearby, it may choose to use a blast power instead of a bolt.\n\nTo avoid accidents, powers that can set things on fire are excluded from this.\n\nDue to the nature of how pawns think, they don't use offensive abilities often, and while undrafted, they only try to use offensive abilities when set to attack nearby targets.</SHG_AutomaticOffenseDescription>
    <SHG_AutomaticOffenseDrafted>        Drafted Auto-Offense</SHG_AutomaticOffenseDrafted>
    <SHG_AutomaticOffenseDraftedDescription>Pawns will try to use the same abiilties as they would while undrafted in a dangerous situation. This is a separate option because you may encounter situations where pawns will keep spamming their offensive abilities at an enemy, even if you were hoping they'd just shoot normally.\n\nDue to the nature of how Rimworld handles jobs, pawns will only attempt to use this when interrupted (i.e. ordered to move to a new location, got hit by an enemy, just finished casting an ability, just got drafted, etc). While this is usually not an issue for supers with one or two offensive abilities, it's recommended to treat this more as an additional help than a primary method of killing enemies, as I can't guarantee that the AI will keep attacking.</SHG_AutomaticOffenseDraftedDescription>

    <SHG_AutomaticFleeing>    Autocast Fleeing Abilities</SHG_AutomaticFleeing>
    <SHG_AutomaticFleeingDescription>While the pawn is undrafted, they will automatically try to use their abilities while fleeing when the situation warrants it. If they are set to flee when enemies are nearby, they will often try to use whatever escape abilities they have at their disposal, from blink to invisibility to heroically leaping away. This includes the vanilla invisibility and longjump legs as methods of last resort.\n\nWarning: While it usually is not an issue, a pawn fleeing from a melee opponent may be so distracted trying to flee that they forget they can teleport. They will try to flee if an enemy is within a range of 20, but there are situations where this may not apply. In conclusion, treat this setting as an assisting autocast rather than an something that always saves pawns.</SHG_AutomaticFleeingDescription>
</LanguageData>
