<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Superhero Genes - Base</name>
  <author>alite</author>
  <packageId>SuperheroGenesBase.Mod</packageId>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.4</li>
    <li>1.5</li>
    <li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
  
  <modDependencies>
    <li>
      <packageId>ludeon.rimworld.biotech</packageId>
      <displayName>Biotech</displayName>
    </li>
    <li>
      <packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
      <displayName>Harmony</displayName>
      <downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
      <steamWorkshopUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
    </li>
  </modDependencies>

  <loadAfter>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
    <li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Biotech</li>
    <li>ceteam.combatextended</li>
    <li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</li>
    <li>sarg.alphagenes</li>
    <li>Sov.Homelander</li>
    <li>vanillaexpanded.achievements</li>
    <li>EBSG.Framework</li>
  </loadAfter>

  <description>
Ever wanted your pawns to be able to lift extreme weights? Want them to be able to research things at frankly ridiculous speeds? This mod allows you to give pawns various super powers that, much like in superhero movies, allows them to ignore the laws of common sense. This currently adds hundreds new genes that aim to make pawns significantly more powerful without becoming so overpowered that they are completely untouchable. This mod will also remove the armor cap for vanilla, assuming a mod before it in your list hasn't already done so.

[url=https://github.com/KonradHeinser/SuperheroGenesBase/wiki]This wiki gives a full list of the genes available and a generic explanation of their effects[/url]
_______________________________________________________

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3088653906]Superhero Genes - Villain and Stereotypes[/url] adds xenotypes that use these genes and a hostile faction. It's separate from this one so that people don't have a bunch of extra xenotypes filling their list, or a hostile faction of strong opponents disrupting their colony constantly.
    
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3321596781]Superhero Genes - Hero Organization[/url] adds non-evil super factions, and for those with royalty it adds a few quests including one to two end-game quests.

_______________________________________________________

[url=https://store.steampowered.com/app/1149640/RimWorld__Royalty/]The Royalty DLC is required for the Psionist archetype and related paths[/url]

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2023507013]The Vanilla Expanded Framework is required for the phasing passive.[/url]

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2925432336]The Big and Small Genes Framework is required for the size changing genes.[/url]

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3112549163]The EBSG Framework is required for a variety of genes, including the equipment flaws, forcefields, and specialized damage boosts.[/url]

_______________________________________________________

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2967228692]Dynamic Carry Capacity[/url] helps fix a vanilla bug that causes carry capacity to not function outside of hauling.

To help avoid inheritance issues caused by the vanilla system, try using a mod like the [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3046776238]Better Gene Inheritence[/url] mod made by RedMattis.

If you want to give a pawn a bunch of powers, you may need something like [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2838035829]Scrollable Gizmos[/url] to make the abilities easier to go look through.

_______________________________________________________


[url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561199377833097/myworkshopfiles/]The preview and mod icon were made by Elseud[/url]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/id/alite/myworkshopfiles/?appid=294100]Easy link to all of my Rimworld mods[/url]

[url=https://github.com/KonradHeinser/SuperheroGenesBase][img]https://i.imgur.com/kTkpTOE.png[/img][/url]
[url=https://ko-fi.com/alite56114][img]https://i.imgur.com/Utx6OIH.png[/img][/url]
[url=https://discord.gg/fYP8qkcNDh][img]https://i.imgur.com/0dG2g3t.png[/img][/url]


For those who are wondering, yes, I have added a CE compatibility patch. Not a particularly good one, but it's there. I do not, nor do I ever plan to, use CE, so the patch is about as balanced as I am personally capable of getting it to. I am not planning on updating the patch, so outside of CE adding a patch in its own mod, it is unlikely that the patch will change.
  </description>
</ModMetaData>

<!--Original textures for some of the powers are available on https://game-icons.net-->
